So the five companies we will cover are
Niba, ICICI, Tata, HDFC and Kth.  These
five are top companies.  Let's
understand which companies they belong to and
which features are good.  Niva BPUPA
's 3.0 It's One of the Best in Global
Covers.  5 Crore cover available from Day One, no waiting
period.  And both planned and
unplanned.  Meaning, even if you are travelling, you
are covered.  If you are planning to leave from here then
also you are covered.  So this is one
beautiful product for global cover.  So
make premier is a good policy.  If
you want to take global cover, you get cover up to Rs 3 crore
and the biggest point is that it
is inbuilt and there is no waiting period.  So
whenever you take the coverage, if the sum
assured is Rs 1 lakh, you will get Rs 50 lakh.   If you buy it for Rs
3 crore, I will take it for Rs 3 crore.  But first you have to
understand that the sum assured should be big when you
talk about global covers outside, small
covers will not work.  But still 3 crore
is ok if you are taking bigger sum assured of
3 crore and inbuilt 3 crore then it
works out valid. There
is one more disadvantage in Tata that you will get only plan, which
means
if you face an emergency while travelling there then there will be no problem.
Now comes the best in class, if we talk then
Nivapa and Elevate both
are good but let us understand Elevate, first there is
unlimited cover in Elevate, whatever cover you have
taken for unlimited, the same unlimited cover is there
here also, you will be fully covered
for both planned and unplanned.  But as a catch, there is a
capping of 45 days in it.  As soon as your 45 days
global cover ends, your cover will end and
you will have to come back and then you
can go after planning.  But that's a problem you ca
n't do.  So, in a way, there is a limit to it
which is not being told but it is a limit.
So on this basis, coverage of Rs 5 crore
is decent sum assured for a travel as
well as for no waiting period, no travel
time.  So if we look at this, Neeva is better.  If we
look at unlimited then ICICI is better.  HDFC
Optima Secure
offers a very good maternity cover with a sum assured of Rs 2 lakh.
That is the maximum overall in all these
five companies, they gave a waiting period of 3 years.   The
coverage is complete but you cannot get the coverage before 3 years.
Baby cover is also Day One
only unlimited cover.  There is no vaccination.
But if you want to get good sum assured and have
time to wait then this is a good plan.
Care has an Advantage plan which includes
global cover.  Under this, coverage ranging from Rs 25 lakh to Rs
3 crore is available.  There will be
profit only if you take Rs 3 crore.  There is
no waiting period, which is an advantage and it
covers both planned and unplanned plans.  This
means you are covered even if you are travelling
and even if you are going for a planned surgery from here, you
are covered.  So Tata's Medik
Premier.  Inside this, the
policy is divided into two parts: girl child and boy
child.  If it is a boy child then Rs 1 lakh will be given
and if it is a girl child then
Rs 1,20,000 will be given.  But there is a disadvantage in this, there is a
waiting period of three years.
Maternity coverage is not available before that.  And the second point is that it does
not have Day One cover inside it.  You will
not get a baby day cover.  If we
talk about vaccination coverage, then there is coverage of 10,000 and 15,000
again boy child and girl child.
But three years is a disadvantage.   The
most crucial point for young parents
which is maternity cover.  Today we need
maternity cover but what coverage are they providing we have
to understand.  So the first thing that is important
in maternity cover is
how much does the cover cost?  Is there a waiting period or not
?  Whether baby day one is covered or not and whether
vaccination is there or not.  So these are the main things which we need
to identify.  And
what are the features of these five companies
?  What are the things, will you
explain?  So first of all we will talk about
Care Joy.  Sum Assured is the minimum sum assured of Rs.
35,000 for Rs. 3 lakh policy
and Rs. 50,000 for Rs. 5 lakh policy, maximum Rs. 50,000 then comes
in waiting period of 9 months and 24
months in both options.  One can exercise if they want to. The
most crucial thing is that the
baby day one cover in it is only Rs 50,000
and that too after waiting for 9 days, meaning it is
not covered from day one.  Actually there is
coverage after 90 days and that too for 500 km.  And there
is no vaccination.  So this is joy today we
talked about five companies HDFC Tata K ICICI
and Neeva BPA and in comparison of them
five features have been told that which features of which company
come on top.  Now it's up to you.
You choose which of these features you
want and choose your company accordingly.  It
is not necessary that the same feature should be dominant.
If you like that feature along with the other
company's features, choose
that company.  Be Healthy And Wish You The Best
To Choose The Right Product For You.